# **Rory Ellis**

Q Grapevine, Texas 
□ rdellis1@gmail.com □ 469-682-2373 in in/roryellis/ 
□ roryellis.github.io/
□ 469-682-2373 in in/roryellis/
□ 469-682-23

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Full-Stack Software Engineer with a broad skillset developed from more than a decade of experience in Data/Analytics, Digital Marketing, Business Process/Systems Development, and general professional problem solving.

I have a passion for building creative solutions to a wide variety of challenges, and I would love to discuss how I can benefit your organization.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, Python

Frameworks/Libraries: ReactJS, ExpressJS, Django, Django-REST-Framework, Bootstrap

Database: SQL - PostgreSQL, Google BigQuery; NoSQL - MongoDB Community/Atlas

Project Management: Agile Development process, Online project management tools such as Jira, Asana, Basecamp, etc.

Digital Marketing Strategy: SEO, SEM, PPC, Paid and Organic Social Media, E-mail, Audience Segmentation and Targeting

Data Analytics Tools: Google Analytics, Google Data Studio, Tableau, MicroStrategy

General Tools: VS Code/Atom/Sublime, MS Office/Excel, Adobe Creative Suite, Google Apps

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineering Immersive Student

#### **General Assembly**

March 2020 - June 2020, Remote

Successfully completed a full-time 420+ hour course of study in full-stack development designed to engrain a solid foundation of Front-End and Back-End development skillsets. I gained the ability to produce functional and robust applications across a wide variety of needs, as well as the ability to quickly and effectively learn and implement new languages and frameworks as needed.

During my course, I completed 4 major projects:

- $\cdot$  HTML/CSS/Javascript recreation of the classic "Simon" game.
- ReactJS based "Riding Weather" application utilizing a 3rd-party weather API, Google Maps Places Library and Geocoder API, and Navigator WebAPI to offer near real-time weather conditions analysis for planning outdoor activities.
- · Group/Pair-Programming implementation of a Customer Relationship Management(CRM) tool using ReactJS and Bootstrap on the Front-End, and an Express/Mongoose/MongoDB Back-End.
- · Localized "Restaurant Offers" application utilizing a PostgreSQL database, Django-Rest-Framework API and responsive ReactJS/Bootstrap Front-End.

#### **Data and Analytics Manager-Marketing**

#### **Park Place Dealerships**

June 2012 - March 2020, Irving, TX

Throughout my involvement with the Park Place Dealership group, I had a hand in a broad range of projects and responsibilities in influencing and supporting our overall marketing strategy and performance across a group of approximately twenty luxury automotive franchise points.

My most recent focus for the organization organization was exploring available data throughout our operational and marketing platforms as well as 3rd party partner sources to enable informed decision–making and identify actionable opportunities to improve marketing tactics, targeting, and performance tracking.

One of my strongest achievements was the automation of cross-departmental sales lead performance reporting, managing a third-party development partner and Google Cloud Platform tools for data transfer, warehousing, and dashboarding.

Other areas of responsibility at Park Place Dealerships included:

- · Website property development, maintenance and functionality support across multiple organization and dealership sites.
- · Inventory system and data feed management.
- · Search Engine Marketing (SEM).
- · Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- · Online Content Marketing.
- · Social Media Marketing.
- · Online product merchandising.
- · Identifying new technologies and opportunities to improve performance and gain market share.
- · Leadership reporting on performance and strategic recommendations.

## Social Media Manager

#### Splash Media

March 2011 - January 2020, Addison, TX

Managed social presence, content marketing, on-page and off-page SEO strategies, graphic design, and overall marketing strategy integration for organizations across multiple venues including Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Youtube video production, and company blogs. Extensive knowledge of the tactics and strategies for each of these platforms allowed me to leverage them in a holistic solution for brand awareness and engagement with existing and prospective clientele.

# Internet Marketing Consultant, National Brands and Franchises

ReachLocal

August 2010 - February 2011, Plano, TX

Consultative selling, account management, and relationship building within assigned franchise brand groups to increase product adoption and educate business owners on the value of online presence. I worked to ensure the success of advertising campaigns for current advertising clients through consultation around business goals and providing recommendations and education for reaching those goals through the use of Search Engine Marketing, Online Display Marketing, and utilizing Social Media as a business tool.

### **Business Development Manager**

**Ellipse Communications** 

November 2008 - August 2010, Addison, TX

Managed sales opportunities by presenting new services, providing development and service proposals, and negotiating service agreements in new and existing accounts in order to implement successful digital marketing strategies for my clients.

## Motorcycle Technician

**Dallas Harley Davidson** 

September 2006 - November 2008, Garland, TX

Responsible for maintenance, diagnosis, and repair of all mechanical and electrical systems on Harley Davidson Motorcycles. I provided excellent customer service and reliable results in a timely manner.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering Immersive Program** 

General Assembly · Remote Classroom · 2020